

#### Burak Kanmaz

Head of Technology



+90 (538) 778 90 86



burak@kanmaz.net



12 Apr, 1987

Burak, who is married and has a child, has been working professionally on Microsoft technologies for more than 12 years. At the same time, it works by following trend technologies regularly and being open to innovations. With its innovative personality, it attaches great importance to quality, performance and efficiency in all its works. It also applies this working principle in team and project management.

### **Work Experiences**



# **Head of Technology**

Inooster April, 2022 - ....

He continues his duty as **Head of Technology** in Turkey's largest gamification company in gamification solutions.

After starting the business, he contributed to the company's product development on **Jira**, which offers a gamification solution. The company, which has a portfolio of more than **20 customers** with **5 products** offering gamification solutions, monitors and manages the technical processes of the products and customers.

It currently continues its business processes with 2 software teams.



#### **Team Lead**

Antasya May, 2021 - April, 2022

As the Team Lead of the 7-person software team that develops tailor-made software for corporate companies, he managed the works and customers. He provided the follow-up, management and customer communication of **15 projects** of 5 corporate companies, including 3 holdings, 1 bank and 1 production facility.

In addition to team management, he also undertook the responsibility of all technical work within the company. Accordingly, he took an active role in the recovery and management of all physical and digital technical assets of the company, the technical coordination of other teams and the determination of the company's future plans.

In addition to these, he took part in all technical communication and management processes with customers during his duty. Helped grow internal teams by interviewing more than 75 jobs. With his experience on the Jira side, he enabled the company to provide **Jira Consulting** to its clients.



# **Solutions Architect**

Ericsson May, 2017 - Apr, 2021

He started to work as a **Senior Software Developer** within a team of 20 people in the call center flow management project of Turkcell, Turkey's largest GSM operator.

In October 2017, he became the person responsible for one of the critical modules within the project. During the year he worked in this position, he took the responsibility of the business as a contact person with the customer and served as a **Lead Developer**.

In October 2018, a team was formed to maintain and

# Areas of Interest and Expertise

#### **Backend Technologies**

.NET Framework, .NET Core, ASP.NET MVC, C#, Java

#### **Frontend Technologies**

Angular, React JS, VueJS, Bootstrap, Typescript

#### **Mobile Technologies**

Flutter, React Native, Ionic, Swift

#### **Data Store/Process Technologies**

EF, MSSQL, PL/SQL, PostreSQL, MongoDB, Redis, RabbitMQ, Solr, Elastic Search (ELK)

#### **DevOps Technologies**

Windows Server, IIS, Linux, Docker, Azure, AWS, Cloudflare, Firewall

#### **Project Management Technologies**

Jira, Confluence, Azure DevOps, Git, TFS, Bitbucket

#### **Administrative Technologies**

Microsoft 365, Exchange, Teams, Azure AD, Azure Cloud, MPN, Cloudflare

# Other

Information Security and Pentest, CFP (Cosmic Function Point), Python

# Technologies He Tries To Lead

Machine Learning, Big Data, Artificial Intelligence, GPT-3, IoT, Raspberry Pi

# **Information Security**

He has been working in the field of information security since 2012 for hobby purposes. During these studies, he provided security consultancy and pentest services to many companies. In addition to information security; He also consulted on **social engineering, penetration testing, network security and application security**. Some of the companies it serves;















develop Turkcell Global Bilgi's corporate applications. He served as **Solutions Architect** at the head of this team, which varied between 10-15 people depending on the project and needs. In this process, he undertook all the processes from the establishment of the team to the management of the relations with the customer. He provided development support and technical support services with his team in 20+ projects of the customer.

In November 2020, he transferred to the CRM project team within Turkcell. Within the scope of this project, he supported the maintenance and development of the Turkcell CRM project with a team of 13 people.



### **IT Manager**

### Istanbul Commodity Exchange 2015 - 2017

He was assigned to manage the information technology team of 5 people and to meet all the software and hardware needs of the company's **120 personnel in 5 different locations**.

Reorganized the network infrastructure where security and authorization were not enough. Adjusted user authorizations, maximizing security and authorization by adjusting internet access rules, file shares and firewall. In addition, it made it all user actions within the network can be monitored, automatically alerted and controlled.



#### **IT Manager Assistant**

Ankara Sigorta 2014 - 2015

He realized that all source codes and databases could be accessed thanks to a security vulnerability he found on the Ankara Insurance website. Following the notification of this vulnerability, he was assigned to the company's 12-person information technology team as **Assistant Manager** responsible for software.

It focused on performance issues in the recently written infrastructure with .NET. It accelerated the processes in various modules that took a very long time by **80-85% by making optimizations** both on the application side and on the database side.



# Senior Software Developer

Doğan Gazetecilik 2012 - 2014

He worked actively during the development of the **Live Score** project, which was developed on the broadcasting of the live results of sports games, especially football. The project was implemented on MSSQL using ASP.NET MVC. He used **Angular JS and Knockout JS** so that the scores could be given to the visitors as quickly as possible. Together with **NetScaler**, it has prepared a system that can serve **65,000 instantaneous visitors** without any performance loss.



# Software Developer

Kariyer.net 2012 - 2012



# Software Developer

IRM Ajans 2009 - 2012

### **Awards and Achievements**

Ö	Ericsson was awarded a special thank you for working remotely during the pandemic period.	2020
Ö	Awarded Ericsson's "MMEA's 2019 Champions Award Winner"	2019
<b>T</b>	Won 1st place in Turkey in Microsoft's international Imagine Cup software competition	2010
*	Selected as Microsoft Student Partner 2 times 2008	3, 2009
i	Wrote a book on Windows 7	2008

# **Educational Background**



#### Postgraduate Computer Engineering

Istanbul University 2022 - ....

He has completed the course phase and is writing a thesis on the subject of **Security Analysis** of Blockchain Based Applications".



# **Undergraduate** Sociology

Istanbul University 2020 - ....

Due to his interest in sociology and psychology, he studies sociology with remote education.



# Undergraduate

Computer Engineering

Istanbul University 2005 - 2010

During his undergraduate life, he served as the computer club president, department student representative and department laboratory assistant.

# Freelance Works

For the Ministry of Youth and Sports; He developed the websites, mobile applications and Olympic management systems of the 2017 Erzurum European Youth Winter Olympics and the 2017 Samsun Deaf Olympics. With this infrastructure, it responded to a total of 30 million requests from visitors during the 2 Olympic Games with a 100% uptime rate and a response time of less than 250 ms.

Currently, he continues to do freelance projects to improve himself and experience new technologies.